Guide to the Morris Edward Opler papers, [ca. 1960-1996]
Opler, Morris Edward papers, [ca. 1960-1996]
- Series I: Apache Indian Tribe
  - Subseries G: Kiowa
    - Navaho Phonetics and Grammar- Kiowa Apache Relationship Terms (Box 51, Folder 4)
- Series II. Navaho Indian Tribe
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Kinship (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence and notes (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence and notes (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Minutes from the Navajo Tribal Council, March 12-13, 1934 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Photographs (Box 47, Folder 8)
- Series III. Miscellaneous Native American Material
  - Plains Indians (Box 46, Folder 22)
  - Southeast Indians (Box 46, Folder 23)
  - Southeast Indians (Box 46, Folder 24)
  - Southeast Indians (Box 46, Folder 25)
  - Southeast Indians (Box 46, Folder 26)
  - Southeast Indians (Box 46, Folder 27)
  - Handbook article (not yet corrected)-Apachean culture pattern and its origins (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Handbook article (not yet corrected)-Chiricahua Apache (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Handbook article (not yet corrected)-Mescalero Apache (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Apache Indian Photograph scrapbook (Box 49)
  - Apache Indian Photograph scrapbook (Box 49)
  - Apache Indian Photograph scrapbook (Box 49)
  - Scrapbook of Photographs from New Mexico and Indian societies (Box 49)
  - Scrapbook of Morris Opler's family and friends (Box 49)
  - Jicarilla card file-vocabulary (Box 50)
  - Chiricahua card file-vocabulary (Box 50)
  - Mescalero card file-vocabulary (Box 50)
  - Mescalero card file-vocabulary (A-Z) (Box 50)
  - Mescalero card file-plants (Botanical-Mescalero) (Box 50)
  - Chiricahua and Mescalero card file-plants (Box 84)
  - Lipan card file-vocabulary (Box 84)
  - Jicarilla card file-vocabulary (Box 84)
  - Jicarilla card file-plants (Box 84)
  - Lipan/Mescalero expenses submitted for reimbursement (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Lipan/Mescalero Texas claims case correspondence (Box 85, Folder 2)
  - Lipan/Mescalero miscellaneous style sheet (Box 85, Folder 3)
  - Lipan-legal material (Box 85, Folder 4)
  - Lipan/Mescalero case-M.E.O. report "The Lipan and Mescalero Apache in Texas" (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - Locations of the Lipan and Mescalero (Box 85, Folder 6)
  - Lipan/Mescalero Neighbors-comments (Box 85, Folder 7)
  - M.E. Opler's analysis of Ysleta (Box 85, Folder 8)
  - Lipan/Mescalero digest dates (Box 85, Folder 9)
  - Verne Ray's digest and cards (Box 85, Folder 10)
  - Verne Ray's digest (Box 85, Folder 11)
  - Verne Ray's digest (Box 85, Folder 12)
  - Lipan/Mescalero locations (Box 85, Folder 13)
  - Lipan/Mescalero locations (Box 85, Folder 14)
  - Lipan/Mescalero bibliography (Box 85, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings, articles, etc. (Box 85, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, articles, etc. (Box 85, Folder 17)
  - Legislation and planning before 1934 (Box 85, Folder 18)
  - Legislation and planning (1934) (Box 85, Folder 19)
  - Legislation and Planning (1934), 86 (Box 85, Folder 20)
  - Indian Claims Commission Docket No. 22-C List and Digest Petitioner's exhibit Nos. 56-362 (Box 86)
  - Indian Claims Commission Docket No. 22-C List and Digest Petitioner's exhibit Nos. 363-580 (Box 86)
  - Legislation and Planning after 1934 (Box 86, Folder 1)
  - Legislation and Planning after 1934 (Box 86, Folder 2)
  - Health (general) (Box 86, Folder 3)
  - Lands, forests, waterways (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - Indian service materials and papers, 1936-1937 (Box 86, Folder 5)
  - Education (general) (Box 86, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous photographs from California (Box 86, Folder 7)
  - Eastern Woodland Indians (Box 86, Folder 8)
  - Eskimo Indians (Box 86, Folder 9)
  - Northwest coast Indians (Box 86, Folder 10)
  - Plains Indians (Box 86, Folder 11)
  - Southeast Indians (Box 86, Folder 12)
  - Southeast Indians (Box 86, Folder 13)
  - Southwest Indians (Box 86, Folder 14)
  - Southwest Indians (Box 86, Folder 15)
  - Southwest Indians (photographs) (Box 86, Folder 16)
  - Education (general) (Box 86, Folder 17)
  - Lipan/Mescalero Digest-1-99 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Lipan/Mescalero Digest-100-199 (Box 88, Folder 2)
  - Lipan/Mescalero Digest-200-299 (Box 88, Folder 3)
  - Lipan/Mescalero Digest-300-399 (Box 88, Folder 4)
  - Lipan/Mescalero Digest-400-499 (Box 88, Folder 5)
  - Lipan/Mescalero Digest-500-599 (Box 88, Folder 6)
  - Lipan/Mescalero Digest (Box 88, Folder 7)
  - Lipan/Mescalero-1-99 (Box 88, Folder 8)
  - Lipan/Mescalero-100-199 (Box 88, Folder 9)
  - Lipan/Mescalero-200-299 (Box 88, Folder 10)
  - Lipan/Mescalero-300-399 (Box 88, Folder 11)
  - Lipan/Mescalero-400-499 (Box 88, Folder 12)
  - Lipan/Mescalero-500-599 (Box 88, Folder 13)
  - Dobyns' Lipan research-card file (Box 88)
- Series IV. Morris Opler's Professional Material
  - American culture (Box 87, Folder 1)
  - American culture (Box 87, Folder 2)
  - Anthropology 349-"The People's of Asia" by Ralph Linton (Box 87, Folder 3)
  - Australia (Box 87, Folder 4)
  - Bibliographies, maps, general (Box 87, Folder 5)
  - Japan-general (Box 87, Folder 6)
  - Japan-cat, dog, snake, etc. (Box 87, Folder 7)
  - Oceania-notes, reports, general (Box 87, Folder 8)
  - Oceania-notes, reports, general (Box 87, Folder 9)
  - Russia (Box 87, Folder 10)
  - Southeast Asia-Bibliographies, maps, etc. (Box 87, Folder 11)
  - Tibet (Box 87, Folder 12)
  - World-peoples of (Box 87, Folder 13)
  - South America (Box 87, Folder 14)
  - Handbook of Native American Indians-orders and shipments (Box 87, Folder 20)
  - University of Buffalo-correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box 87, Folder 21)
  - University of Chicago-correspondence, 1987-1992 (Box 87, Folder 22)
  - Cornell University correspondence, 1974-1993 (Box 87, Folder 23)
  - University of Oklahoma-miscellaneous (Box 87, Folder 24)
  - Appointment to University of Oklahoma, 1969 (Box 87, Folder 25)
  - General Information (Box 87, Folder 26)
  - National Science Foundation Grant, 1974-1976 (Box 87, Folder 27)
  - Publication information (Box 87, Folder 28)
  - National Foundation on the Arts and Humanities (Box 87, Folder 29)
  - American Anthropological Association-correspondence, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 30)
  - American Anthropological Association-constitution, etc. (Box 87, Folder 31)
  - American Folklore Society (Box 87, Folder 32)
  - Center for Advanced Study in Behavior Sciences-Stanford (Box 87, Folder 33)
  - Tibetan Program-correspondence, 1966-1977 (Box 87, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence with students (Box 87, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence with students (Box 87, Folder 36)
  - Subseries A: 515- Anthropological Theory
    - Course Materials (General) (#1) (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Course Outlines, Book Reserve Lists, Course Materials of Others (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous (#1): MSS (A-G) (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous (#2): MSS (H) (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous (#3): MSS (I-P) (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous (#4): MSS (Q-Wh) (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous (#7): Newspaper Clippings, Magazine Articles, etc. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Student Papers (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Bibliographies (Master file) (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Departmental Seminar (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Values: Seminar (Cornell Faculty) (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Values: General (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Values and Themes Bibliographies (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - MEO Themes: Nostrand (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Marxism: Totalitarian Theory (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Concepts Course, 1948 (MEO copy) (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Methodology (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - MEO Themes: Manuscripts and Articles (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - MEO Themes: Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - MEO Themes: Notes (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Student Papers (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Subseries B: 301- Cultural Anthropology
    - Course Notes (General) (#1) (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Course Notes (General) (#2) (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Subseries C: 424- Comparative Religious Systems
    - Bibliographies (Master File) (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Course Notes (General) (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Lectures and Papers of Others (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Folklore (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Peyote (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Subseries D: 265- Culture and Personality
    - Course Notes (General) (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Bibliographies (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Work and Summaries of Others (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Manuscripts, Printed Materials, etc. (Folder #1) (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Manuscripts, Printed Materials, etc. (Folder #2) (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Minturn- Socialization (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - McClelland- Achievement (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Carstairs- Hijara (India) (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Subseries E: Course Notes
    - Physical Anthropology (#1)- General (Course Notes, Reports) (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Physical Anthropology (Kennedy) (#2) (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Physical Anthropology (#3)- Anth. 545, Palaeoanthropology of So. Asia (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Physical Anthropology (#4) Organic- Cultural MS. (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Race (A--B) (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Race (C--I) (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Race (J--R) (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Race (S--Z) (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Race (Coon, Carleton S.) (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Linguistics- General (Bibliographies, Reports, Newspaper Clippings, etc.) (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Archaeology- General (Course Notes, Reports) (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Subseries F: Unpublished and Miscellaneous
    - A (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - B (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - C (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - D (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - E (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - F (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - G (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - H (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - I (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - J (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - K (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - L (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - L (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - M (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - N (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - O (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - P (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Q (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - R (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - S (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - T (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - U (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - V (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - W (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - X, Y, Z (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Subseries G: Theory: Tylor, Edward B.
    - Writings, 1860-69 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Writings, 1870-74 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Writings, 1875-79 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Writings, 1880-84 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Writings, 1885-89 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Writings, 1890-94 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Writings, 1895-99 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Writings, 1900- (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Items re: Tylor, A-C (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Items re: Tylor, D (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Items re: Tylor, E-K (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Items re: Tylor, L (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Items re: Tylor, M (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Items re: Tylor, N-Z (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Background Material, A-B (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Background Material, C-G (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Background Material, H-L (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Background Material, R-S (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Background Material, T-Z (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Subseries H: Slides
    - India (Box 99, Folder A)
    - India and Nepal (Box 99, Folder B)
    - Nepal and Sikkim, Kuti, Banaras, Lucknow, Sonawal (Box 99, Folder C)
    - Navaho (Box 100, Folder D)
    - Mescalero and Chiricahua (Box 100, Folder E)
    - Mescalero, Navaho, Chiricahua, Hopi, Misc. American Indian (Box 100, Folder F)
    - Personal Slides: NW Europe, NW Coast, Western US, Rockies, Plains Southwest (Box 100, Folder G)
    - Western Apache, Pueblo Indians, El Morro, Jicarilla, Philbrook and Catlin Paintings (Box 101, Folder I)
    - Cherokees, Pueblos, Bandelier, National Monuments (Box 101, Folder J)
    - Desert Flowers, Bryce Canyon, Grand Canyon, Great Smokey Mtns. (Box 101, Folder K)
    - Great Smokies, Old Salem, Charlottesville, Misc. (Box 101, Folder L)
    - Carter's Grove, Huntington Library, Salt Lake City, Zion Nat'l Park, Pleasant Valley Raches, SW Archaeology, OK City Zoo, Philbrook Art Center, Gilcrease Institute, Cedar Breaks Nat'l Monument (Box 101, Folder M)
    - Sonawal (cont'd from C) (Box 101, Folder N)
    - Personal Slides: Railroads, Museums, Nat'l Monuments (Box 101, Folder O)
    - Picuris Pueblo, Hopi Dancers, Navajos, Canyon de Chelly, Inn of the Mt. Gods, Old Santa Fe Trail Landmarks (Box 101, Folder P)
    - Navaho Coyoteway (Box 101, Folder Q)
    - Personal Slides: San Diego Zoo, Glen Canyon Dam and Lake Powell, Flagstaff (Box 101, Folder R)
    - Index to India Color Slides (Box 105, Folder 3)
    - (smaller box) India Color Slides (Box 105, Folder 4)
    - (small box) India Color Slides (Box 105, Folder 5)
    - Bill Rowe, 151-300 (Color) (Box 106, Folder 1)
    - Barney Cohn I (Box 106, Folder 2)
    - Barney Cohn II, Allen Atwell (Senapur only), Unidentified Senapur Photographer (Box 106, Folder 3)
    - Shirley Marshall Planalp (SM or SP) (Box 106, Folder 4)
    - Kenneth Morgan (Box 106, Folder 5)
    - Bill Rowe, 1-150 (Color) (Box 106, Folder 6)
    - India, General (Box 107, Folder 1)
    - India, General (Box 107, Folder 1)
    - Bill Rowe, 301-389 (Color); Jack Planalp (Box 107, Folder 2)
    - Bob Smith, 1-92 (Color); David Wilson, 1-34 (Color) (Box 107, Folder 3)
    - American Indian (Box 107, Folder 4)
    - Arail (General) (Box 107, Folder 5)
    - Arail (Magh Mela and General), Allen Atwell (General) (Box 107, Folder 6)
- Series V: Manzaner Japanese Internment Camp
  - Manzanar Guayule tire (Box 52)
  - Manzanar evacuation and bibiliography-card file (Box 52)
  - Japanese Internment Redress Bill, 1987 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Manzanar items with pages missing (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Letters from Manzanar to M.E. Opler, 1944-1945 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Guide to the Japanese-American Relocation Centers (Cornell archives), 1935-1953 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Manzanar materials (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence with the Cornell archives, Bob Smith, Angus Macbeth, etc., 1982 (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - War Relocation Authority memorandum, Jan. 1, 1944 (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Frank Churman-copy of his manuscript made by the Fullerton Oral History Project (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - "The Manzanar 'Riot'" An Ethic Perspective" by Arthur A. Hansen and David A. Hacker (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - "Roger Baldwin: A Remembrance", 1982 (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous articles, phamplets, etc., 1940's (Box 53, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous articles, phamplets, etc., 1940's (Box 53, Folder 12)
  - War Relocation Documentation, 1943-1944 (Box 53, Folder 13)
  - Legal War documentation, 1944-1948 (Box 53, Folder 14)
  - Legal documents from the State of California (Box 53, Folder 15)
  - Outline of Yakushuo Dissertation (Box 53, Folder 16)
  - Japanese American Oral History Project (Conducted by California State University), 1978 (Box 53, Folder 17)
  - Japanese American Oral History Program transcripts (Box 53, Folder 18)
  - Japanese American Oral History Project-Fullerton correspondence, 1979 (Box 53, Folder 19)
  - Hirabayashi v. the United States (Box 53, Folder 20)
  - Hawaiian Supreme Court Cases, 1942-1944 (Box 53, Folder 21)
  - Oyama v. the State of California, 1948 (Box 53, Folder 22)
  - Y. Oshio Supreme Court case (Box 53, Folder 23)
  - War Relocation Authority names, staff, etc. (Box 53, Folder 24)
  - Supreme Court Cases including Korematsu v. the United States (Box 53, Folder 25)
  - Peter Suzuki correspondence, etc., 1980-1981 (Box 53, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1943-1948 (Box 53, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1942-1944 (Box 53, Folder 28)
  - Takahashi Supreme Court Case, 1947 (Box 53, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence with evacuees (A-K), 1945-1948 (Box 53, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence with evacuees (L-S), 1944-1946 (Box 53, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence with evacuees (T-Z), 1945-1976 (Box 53, Folder 32)
  - Japanese American Project of the Oral History Program at California State University-Interview with Robert L. Brown, 1973-1974 (Box 53)
  - War Relocation Authority Documentation (Box 53, Folder 33)
  - "The Loyalty Controversy-A Statement and a Suggested Program", 1943 (Box 53, Folder 34)
  - Paper read before the American Anthropological Association, Nov. 18, 1978 (Box 53, Folder 35)
  - Japanese magazine, 1947 (Box 53)
  - Infantry Journal, March 1947 (Box 53)
  - Summation of Non-Military Activities in Japan, September 1946 (Box 53)
  - Infantry Journal, April 1947 (Box 53)
  - Japanese Social Structure (Box 53)
  - Manzanar Scrapbook, 1942-1944 (Box 54)
  - Manzanar Scrapbook, 1942-1944 (Box 54)
  - Manzanar evacuation and bibliography-card file (A-K) (Box 54)
  - Manzanar evacuation and bibliography-card file (H-R) (Box 54)
  - Manzanar evacuation and bibliography-card file (L-Z) (Box 54)
  - Manzanar evacuation and bibliography-card file (S-Z) (Box 54)
  - Pacific Citizen newspaper, 1982 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Pacific Citizen newspaper, 1983 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Pacific Citizen newspaper, 1983 (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Pacific Citizen newspaper, 1984 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Pacific Citizen newspaper, 1983 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous newspaper articles (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous newspaper articles (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous newspaper articles (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous newspaper articles (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous newspaper articles (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous newspaper articles (Box 55, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous newspaper articles (Box 55, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous newspaper articles (Box 55, Folder 13)
  - Japanese drawings (Box 58, Folder 6)
- Series VI: India
  - Card files (Box 56)
  - Card files (Box 57)
  - Keys to Senapur file materials (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Senapur file materials (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Senapur research-general, Jan. 7, 1953 (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - Senapur research on agriculture and animal husbandry, Oct. 10, 1952 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Senapur research on agriculture and animal husbandry, Oct. 10, 1952 (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Research on community action, May 31, 1949 (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Research on National Extension Service, April 30, 1955 (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - Research on public health and children, June 18, 1954 (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - Research on school, Nov., 1952 (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - Animals-general, 1944 (Box 59, Folder 10)
  - Attitudes towards foreigners-general, Oct. 6, 1952 (Box 59, Folder 11)
  - Case histories-general, Jan. 13, 1953 (Box 59, Folder 12)
  - Caste-general, Feb. 19, 1947-Dec. 20, 1947 (Box 59, Folder 13)
  - Caste-general, Feb. 19, 1947-Dec. 20, 1947 (Box 59, Folder 14)
  - Caste-general, Jan. 3, 1948-Dec. 21, 1952 (Box 59, Folder 15)
  - Caste-general, Jan. 10, 1953-Dec. 1, 1955 (Box 59, Folder 16)
  - Caste-general, Jan. 11, 1956-1966 (Box 59, Folder 17)
  - Caste-Ahira, Feb. 25, 1947-April, 1966 (Box 59, Folder 18)
  - Caste-Barais, March 20, 1947-1955 (Box 59, Folder 19)
  - Caste-Bari, March 18, 1947-Nov. 18, 1955 (Box 59, Folder 20)
  - Caste-Bhar, March 10, 1947-Feb. 23, 1956 (Box 59, Folder 21)
  - Caste-Bhat, 1947-1956 (Box 59, Folder 22)
  - Caste-Brahman, 1947-1968 (Box 59, Folder 23)
  - Caste-Brahman, 1947-1968 (Box 59, Folder 24)
  - Caste-Chaman, 1947-1959 (Box 59, Folder 25)
  - Caste-Chamar, 1947-1959 (Box 59, Folder 26)
  - Caste-Dafali, 1947-1956 (Box 59, Folder 27)
  - Caste-Dharikar, 1947-1956 (Box 59, Folder 28)
  - Caste-Dhobi, 1947-1955 (Box 59, Folder 29)
  - Caste-Dhunia, 1947-1956 (Box 59, Folder 30)
  - Caste-Gond, 1947-1968 (Box 59, Folder 31)
  - Caste-Hela, 1947-1956 (Box 59, Folder 32)
  - Caste-Kahar, 1947-1966 (Box 59, Folder 33)
  - Caste-Kalvar, 1947-1955 (Box 59, Folder 34)
  - Caste-Kandu, 1947-1955 (Box 59, Folder 35)
  - Caste-Kahatik, 1947-1955 (Box 59, Folder 36)
  - Caste-Kohar, 1947-1961 (Box 59, Folder 37)
  - Caste-Lohar, 1947-1958 (Box 59, Folder 38)
  - Caste-Musahar, 1947-1956 (Box 59, Folder 39)
  - Caste-Muslim, 1947-1966 (Box 59, Folder 40)
  - Caste-Nai, 1947-1957 (Box 59, Folder 41)
  - Keys to Senapur file materials (Box 59, Folder 42)
  - Caste-Nonia, 1947-1954 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Caste-Nonia, 1947-1957 (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Caste-Teli, 1947-1955 (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Caste-Thakur, 1946-1952 (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Caste-Thakur, 1946-1956 (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Caste tension and caste attitude studies (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - Caste tension study-Senapur and Borsar (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - Caste tension study-Senapur and Borsar (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - Caste tension study-Senapur high caste responses (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - Caste tension study-Senapur low caste responses (Box 60, Folder 10)
  - Caste tension study-Senapur low caste responses (Box 60, Folder 11)
  - Caste tension study-Senapur-Ahir (Box 60, Folder 12)
  - Caste tension study-Senapur-Bania (Box 60, Folder 13)
  - Caste tension study-Senapur-Chamar (Box 60, Folder 14)
  - Caste tension study-Senapur-Chamar (Box 60, Folder 15)
  - Caste tension study-Senapur-Chamar (Box 60, Folder 16)
  - Caste tension study-Senapur-Lohar (Box 60, Folder 17)
  - Caste tension study-Senapur-Thakur (Box 60, Folder 18)
  - Caste tension study-Senapur-Thakur (Box 60, Folder 19)
  - Caste tension study-Senapur-Nonia (Box 60, Folder 20)
  - Caste tension study-Senapur-Nonia (Box 60, Folder 21)
  - Caste tension study-Borsar, Bhar and Chamar (Box 60, Folder 22)
  - Caste tension study-Borsar, Bhar and Chamar (Box 60, Folder 23)
  - Caste tension study-Borsar low caste responses (Box 60, Folder 24)
  - Caste tension study-Borsar high-caste responses (Box 60, Folder 25)
  - Caste tension study-Senapur-Thakur (Box 60, Folder 26)
  - Caste tension study-Kori (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Caste tension study-Borsar-Kori (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Caste tension study-Borsar Thakur (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Caste tension study-Borsar Thakur (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Caste attitude study-Senapur and Borsar (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Caste attitude study-Senapur high caste responses (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - Caste attitude study-Senapur low caste responses (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - Caste attitude study-Senapur low caste responses (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - Caste attitude study-Senapur-Ahir (Box 61, Folder 9)
  - Caste attitude study-Senapur-Ahir (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - Caste attitude study-Senapur-Bania (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - Caste attitude study-Senapur-Chamar (Box 61, Folder 12)
  - Caste attitude study-Senapur-Chamar (Box 61, Folder 13)
  - Caste attitude study-Senapur-Chamar (Box 61, Folder 14)
  - Caste attitude study-Senapur-Lohar (Box 61, Folder 15)
  - Caste attitude study-Senapur (Nonia) (Box 61, Folder 16)
  - Caste attitude study-Senapur (Nonia) (Box 61, Folder 17)
  - Caste attitude study-Senapur (Thakur) (Box 61, Folder 18)
  - Caste attitude study-Senapur (Thakur) (Box 61, Folder 19)
  - Caste attitude study-Borsar (High caste responses) (Box 61, Folder 20)
  - Caste attitude study-Borsar (Low caste response) (Box 61, Folder 21)
  - Caste attitude study-Borsar (Bhar and Chamar) (Box 61, Folder 22)
  - Caste attitude study-Borsar (Bhar and Chamar) (Box 61, Folder 23)
  - Caste attitude study-Borsar (Koiri) (Box 61, Folder 24)
  - Caste attitude study-Borsar (Koiri) (Box 61, Folder 25)
  - Caste attitude study-Borsar (Thakur) (Box 61, Folder 26)
  - Caste attitude study-Borsar (Thakur) (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Change, 1947-1953 (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - Change, 1953-1954 (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Change, 1955-1957 (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Change interview guide and responses, 1955-1957 (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - Change interview guide and responses, 1956 (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Change-Kuti, 1961-1968 (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Seminars, papers, reports and memos on change in Senapur, 1951-1956 (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - Seminars, papers, reports and memos on change in Senapur, 1954-1964 (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - Seminars, papers, reports and memos on change in Senapur, 1954-1964 (Box 62, Folder 10)
  - Concepts, 1947-1965 (Box 62, Folder 11)
  - Conflict and crime, 1947-1953 (Box 62, Folder 12)
  - Conflict and crime, 1953-1954 (Box 62, Folder 13)
  - Conflict and crime, 1955 (Box 62, Folder 14)